novasol.com 2019-12-02

# Cookie and Privacy Policy | NOVASOL

This is NOVASOL’s Data Protection Policy which contains information about how we collect, use, share and protect personal data.

## 1.    Responsiblity for your personal data

www.novasol.dk and other NOVASOL websites and catalogues are owned and maintained by NOVASOL A/S, Virumgårdsvej 27, 2830 Virum, Denmark.   
All enquiries concerning data protection can be sent to the following email address: datainformation@novasol.com   
NOVASOL is responsible for the correct management of the personal data which you send to us. We keep and process your personal data in accordance with data protection and privacy laws.

## 2.    Information which is collected and processed

About guests:  
When you book the rental of a holiday home though NOVASOL, we process the personal data that you send us in connection with your booking. Typically, this will be your name, your address, telephone number, possible email address and payment information.  
About house owners:  
When you choose to let your holiday home through a contract with NOVASOL, we process the personal data that you submit in connection with entering into the contract. Typically, this will be your name, your address, telephone number, possible email address, bank account information and information about your holiday home.  
Generally:  
When you use our website, we collect data about your use of the website via cookies. For further information about cookies and how use them, please see our Cookie Policy.

## 3.    Purpose of the processing of personal data

The personal data you submit to us, can be used for various reasons, depending on your relationship with NOVASOL, for example:  
•    to complete your booking, when you make a booking with NOVASOL  
•    to fulfill our contractual obligations when you let your holiday home through NOVASOL  
•    for statistical purposes in order to optimize letting and to improve our service to you  
•    to make repeat visits to our website more personal  
•    to inform you about offers and other services we believe are of interest to you  
•    to process customer service enquiries; and  
•    to send you information that you have asked for.

## 4.    Legal basis for processing personal data

When you book the rental of a holiday home through NOVASOL, or when you enter into a contract with NOVASOL for the letting of your holiday home, you receive specific information about the legal basis for the processing of your personal data.   
We process personal data on the basis of one of the following lawful grounds:  
Performance of a contract  
With guests:  
When you book the rental of a holiday home through NOVASOL, we process the personal data that you send us in connection with your booking because it is necessary to do so in order to complete the booking and comply with the contract. In the event that you are not willing to give us this information, we will not be able to complete your booking.   
With house owners:  
When you let your holiday home through a contract with NOVASOL, we process the personal data that you submit when you enter into the contract, as well as information about your holiday home, because it is necessary to do so in order to carry out and optimize letting and comply with our contractual obligations. In the event that you are not willing to give us this information, we will not be able to fulfil our obligations under the contract.    
Legitimate interest  
With guests:  
When you book the rental of a holiday home through NOVASOL, we process the personal data that you send us in connection with your booking because we would like to contact you with good offers. This processing of your personal data is carried out on the basis of our legitimate interest in maintaining contact with you in the hope that you will rent a holiday home through us in the future. You can therefore expect that we will contact you on an ongoing basis with offers.   
With house owners:  
When you let your holiday home through a contract with NOVASOL, we process the personal data you submit when you enter into the contract because we would like to contact you after the termination of the contract with offers related to reestablishing our cooperation. This processing of your personal data is carried out on the basis of our legitimate interest in maintaining contact with you and thereby promoting the possibility of reestablishing our cooperation. You can therefore expect that we will contact you after the termination of the contract with offers and information which are relevant for you when deciding whether to reestablish letting through NOVASOL.  
You are entitled at all times to ask us to stop sending marketing materiel to you. You can do that by contacting us at the following e-mail address: datainformation@novasol.com.  
Generally:  
We use some personal data for statistical purposes in order to optimize our service to you. This processing is carried out on the basis of our interest in offering the best possible service.  
We sometimes transfer encrypted email addresses to partners such as Facebook and Google so that they can use them on behalf of NOVASOL to generate interest in our products, services and concepts, and to inspire users to visit our website. We also use our customer data with third party review sites, such as Trustpilot, and it is therefore possible that you will receive an enquiry asking for your comments about your stay in the holiday home and/or the services you have received from us.  This processing is carried out on the basis of our interest in targeting our marketing and providing the best possible service.   
You are entitled at all times to object to the processing of your personal data for the above-mentioned purposes. You can do that by contacting us at the following e-mail address: datainformation@novasol.com  
Consent  
We do not share your personal data with any business partners with a view to them contacting you directly with good offers etc., unless you have given your separate consent to that.   
If we use pictures or videos of you for marketing purposes, we ask for your consent to do so before use.   
You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at the following e-mail address: datainformation@novasol.com.  
Legal obligation  
When legislation requires us to do so, we will also process your personal data on the basis of that legal obligation.

## 5.    Transfer of personal data

To the extent that it is necessary to do so, NOVASOL transfers relevant personal data to house owners/guests, other companies within the NOVASOL group of companies, business partners such as travel agents, holiday property rental websites, credit card companies, insurance companies and cleaning companies as well as to public authorities, in order to carry out and optimize letting and thereby comply with our obligations, in order to be able to request correct and secure payment, or to the extent that it may be necessary in relation to applicable legislation.  
If you have given your separate consent, we transfer your personal data to chosen business partners with a view to them contacting you with good offers etc.  You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at the following e-mail address: datainformation@novasol.com.  
NOVASOL only transfers personal data to countries outside of the EU/EØS to the extent that it is necessary to do so and only when we have ensured that adequate levels of protection are in place.  This may be on the basis that the European Commission has decided that the country in question ensures an adequate level of protection, or via the ”Privacy Shield” programme, or with an agreement in a standard form approved by the European Commission. You can obtain more detailed information in this regard by contacting us at the following e-mail address: datainformation@novasol.com

##   
6.    Period of retention

We keep your personal data only for as long as it is necessary to do so, either in relation to the purpose for which we obtained it or in relation to applicable legislation. We delete your personal data, when it is no longer necessary for us to keep it.

## 7.    Your rights

You are entitled to receive information as to the personal data we have registered about you and to correct any inaccuracies. You are entitled to receive a copy of the personal data that we hold about you.  
You are entitled to obtain the deletion of your personal data if the data is no longer necessary to achieve the purpose for which the data was collected or if the processing is unlawful.   
You are entitled to ask us to limit the processing of your personal data.   
You are entitled to ask us to stop sending you marketing material.   
You are entitled to receive your personal data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to have your personal data transferred directly to another data controller if it is technically feasible to do so.  
You are entitled to make a complaint to a supervisory authority.    
You are entitled to withdraw your consent if we process your personal data on the basis of your consent.   
All enquiries concerning your rights can be sent to the following e-mail address: datainformation@novasol.com

## 8.    Other websites

Our website can contain links to other websites. This data protection policy only applies to our website, so if you use links to other websites we recommend that you read their data protection policy.

## 9.    Updating our data protection policy

We regularly review our data protection policy and we place updates on our website.   
This policy was last updated in May 2018.   
All enquiries concerning data protection can be sent to the following email address: datainformation@novasol.com
